José Luis Redondo García EURECOM, 450 Route des Chappes, 06410

Biot, France

\$\pi +33 \, 652 \, 780 \, 577\$

\times \text{redondo@eurecom.fr}

\tilde{\text{\text{\text{in}}}} \text{jluisred.github.io}

\tilde{\text{\text{\text{\text{in}}}} \text{jluisred}

\text{\text{\text{\text{\text{in}}}} \text{jluisred}

\text{\text{\text{\text{\text{\text{in}}}} \text{jluisred}

\text{\text{\text{\text{\text{\text{in}}}} \text{jluisred}

\text{\text{\text{\text{\text{\text{in}}}} \text{jluisred}

S iluisred



"Only a proper contextualization process leveraging on the vast knowledge available on the Web, can enable machines to effectively turn raw Data into valuable Information"

#### About me

José Luis is currently a last year Phd Student in the Multimedia Communications Department at EURECOM, in France. He has been involved in EU projects like LinkedTV, MediaMixer and NexGenTV, and his research interests include Semantic Web, Multimedia Technologies and Knowledge Representation focusing on the annotation of News Stories.

He is truly convinced that the use of advanced information extraction techniques, combined with the prior knowledge available on the Web and semantic approaches leveraging on them, can drastically improve the way we exploit textual and audiovisual data.

### Areas of Specialization

Semantic Web, Ontology Modeling, Knowledge Representation, Multimedia, Information Extraction, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning

### Education

2012-2016 Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science and Multimedia, EURECOM, Télécom ParisTech, Sophia Antipolis, Nice, France.

Semantically Capturing and Representing Contextualized News Stories on the Web. International news stories in textual and audiovisual form come full of connotations, codes, conventions and implicit paradigms, involve very different agents in many locations, and deliver partial information thus neglecting the whole picture of the event that is often assumed as known. In this Phd I explored how to leverage on the data available in the Web for summarizing into a single knowledge unit the contextual information necessary for making sense of the news story being told, providing humans and machines with details that were not explicitly included in the original document.

2011-2012 MSc. in Computer Science, *University of Extremadura*, Cáceres, Spain. (Avg. score: 9,60/10).

Improving Linked Data Consuming Processes in OntoTV through the use of Ontology Alignment Techniques. The process of integrating Linked Data sources in information systems involves high temporal costs and manual-based efforts to reconcilie different data schemas, therefore attenuating the great advantages that LD can offer over conventional data retrieving methods. This research proposes the use of ontology alignment techniques in order to minimize the impact of these problems.

- 2010-2011 MSc. in Research, University of Extremadura, Master MUI-TINC, Cáceres, Spain. (Avg. score: 9,050/10).
  - Applying Linked Data Methodologies in a Television Content Management System Application of Linked Data methodologies in the television domain in order to improve viewer's watching experience. As part of the implementation of the OntoTV television framework, we have developed different components for ingesting information from Linked Data sources. The reconciled and enriched information has been published according to the same Linked Data Principles so it becomes available in the Web of Data.
- 2010-2011 BS in Computer Science and Systems, University of Extremadura, Cáceres, Spain. (Avg. score: 8,320/10).
- 2008-2009 BS in Computer Science for Business Processes, University of Extremadura, Cáceres, Spain. (Avg. score: 8,350/10).
- 2003-2008 Degree in Computer Science, University of Extremadura, Cáceres, Spain. (AVG. Score: 8,214/10).

Multimedia Interactive Applications over Digital Terrestrial Television The new interactive approaches in digital television and transmission standards like DVB-T offer an interesting variety of services for both producers and consumers. In this project, a Multimedia Home Platform (MHP) based framework has been developed for probing the efficiency of this low-cost solution technologies in supporting viewers when consuming content.

### Experience

- 2011-2012 Research Assistant, Quercus Engineering Group, University of Extremadura (UEX), Cáceres, Spain.
  - Development of an ontology-based management system for digital television that harmonizes content descriptions from various existing sources and represent them by using knowledge engineering. Search and recommendation operations over the collected data are offered in order to improve the viewers' experience.
- 2009-2011 Software Developer, Quercus Engineering Group, Cáceres, Spain.

  Development of a Java application (WeAPoN) for designing administrative processes and converting them into RDF according to a domain specific ontology. The workflows are graphically specified by using Petri nets diagrams that are converted into an ontological representation. We leverage on the resulting graphs to automatically generate Web applications that implement the desired administrative workflow.
- 2007-2008 Research Assistant, Group of Applied Telematics Engineering and Advanced Communications, Cáceres, Spain.
  - Study of valid scenarios for developing interactive Multimedia Home Platform applications by using low-cost components, together with the implementation of different digital interactive applications for deploying e-learning services over DVB-T channels.

## Projects

- 2015-2016 Next Generation TV, Enriched content on interactive TV devices, Fonds unique interministériel (FUI) Call 19, 3 academic and 2 industrial partners.
- 2015-2016 3Cixty, Enabling Visitors to Explore a Smart City, EIT Digital, Knowledge and Innovation Community of the European Institute of Innovation and Technology, 10

academic and 5 industrial partners.

an EIT Digital initiative

- 2011-2015 LinkedTV, Television linked to the Web, FP7 IP Call 5, 8 academic and 4 industrial partners.
  - Integrated and practical approach towards experiencing Networked Media in the Future Internet
- 2012-2014 MediaMixer, Community set-up and networking for the reMIXing of online MEDIA fragments, FP7 CSA Call 8, 5 academic and 3 industrial partners.
- 2011-2012 PD10006, Regional Founding for Young Researchers, Junta de Extremadura, Spain.
- 2009-2011 TIN2008-02985, National Research Project, Spanish Ministry of Education and Science, Spain.

# Awards and Scholarships

- 2015 **Best Paper Award**, K-CAP 2015 Conference, Palisades, New York, U.S., October 7th 10th.
  - The Concentric Nature of News Semantic Snapshots: Knowledge Extraction for Semantic Annotation of News Items
- Semantic Web Challenge, ISWC 2015 Conference, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, U.S.,
   October 11th 15th.
   3cixty@Expo Milano 2015: Enabling Visitors to Explore a Smart City.
- 2010-2012 **3 year PhD scholarship** , Spanish Ministry of Education and Science, Cáceres, Extremadura, Spain, October 11th 15th.

  Consuming Information about Television Content from Linked Data Sources

### **Publications**

- Google https://scholar.google.es/citations?user=YY37C-4AAAAJ&hl=en, h-index=6 Scholar and i10-index=4.
- DBLP http://dblp.uni-trier.de/pers/hd/g/Garc=iacute=a:Jos=eacute=\_Luis\_Redondo.
- Research https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Jose\_Garcia130.
- Key Publi- Redondo Garcia J. L., Rizzo G., Troncy R., Capturing News Stories Once, cations Retelling a Thousand Ways, 8th International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'15), Palisades, NY, USA, October 2015.
  - Rizzo G., Troncy R. et Al., 3cixty@Expo Milano 2015: Enabling Visitors to Explore a Smart City, 14th International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC'15) Semantic Web Challenge, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, USA, October 2015.
  - Redondo Garcia J. L., Rizzo G., Troncy R. , The Concentric Nature of News Semantic Snapshots: Knowledge Extraction for Semantic Annotation of News Items, 8th International Conference on Knowledge Capture (K-CAP'15), Palisades, NY, USA, October 2015.
  - Redondo Garcia J. L., Rizzo G., Romero L. P., Hildebrand M., Troncy R., Generating Semantic Snapshots of Newscasts using Entity Expansion, 15th International Conference on Web Engineering (ICWE'15), Rotterdam, the Netherlands, June 2015.
  - Redondo Garcia J. L., Sabatino M., Lisena P., Troncy R., Finding and sharing hot spots in Web Videos, 13th International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC'14), Riva del Garda, Italy, October 2014.

Redondo Garcia J. L., Hildebrand M., Perez Romero L., Troncy R., Augmenting TV Newscasts via Entity Expansion, 11th Extended Semantic Web Conference (ESWC'14), Riva del Garda, Italy, May 2014.

Redondo Garcia J. L., De Vocht L., Troncy R., Mannens E., Van de Walle R., Describing and Contextualizing Events in TV News Show, (WWW'14) 2nd International Workshop on Social News on the Web (SNOW'14), Seoul, South Korea, April 2014.

### Software Tools and Prototypes

- 2014 **HyperTED**, http://linkedtv.eurecom.fr/Hyperted/, An innovative way of consuming TED talks, Consuming particular chapters, key fragments highlighting, spotting relevant entities, and seamlessly jump to related resources on the Web like other chapters and educational courses.
- 2014 **LinkedTV News**, http://linkedtv.project.cwi.nl/news/, Expanding News with Named Entities, Helping the users to interpret international news via relevant entities playing a role in the depicted story.
- 2013 **MediaFinder**, http://mediafinder.eurecom.fr, What fresh media are you looking for?, Web framework which creates visual illustrations from media items shared by the crowd on social platforms.
- 2012 **Github/jluisred**, https://github.com/jluisred, Tools, services and apps implemented and under development for the different project mentioned above.

### Other Activities

#### PC Member

WWW2016, 25th International World Wide Web Conference, (Poster/Demo Track). SIMBig2015, 2nd International Symposium on I. Management and Big Data. ISWC2015, 14th International Semantic Web Conference, (Poster/Demo Track). ESWC2015, 12th European Semantic Web Conference, (Poster/Demo Track). ISWC2014, 13th International Semantic Web Conference, (Poster/Demo Track). ESWC2014, 11th Extended Semantic Web Conference, (Poster/Demo Track). SIMBig2014, 1st International Symposium on I. Management and Big Data. Subreviewer for HT2014, 25th ACM Conference on Hypertext and Social Media. Mentoring

- 2015 Chaima Ben Rabah, Collecting microposts shared on social networks and reconstructing timelines of events.
- 2014 Mariella Sabatino and Pasquale Lisena, Searching and browsing through fragments of TED Talks and Developing a Media Fragment Server on Node.js.
- 2014 **Phan Trung**, Grab your Favourite TV Show and Share it.

## **L**anguages

Spanish Native.

English Full professional proficiency.

French Professional working proficiency.